'use strict';const questions=[{question:"Radius of a circle is 7 cm, find its area",optionA:"144",optionB:"14",optionC:"184",optionD:"7",correctOption:"optionB"},{question:"121 divided by 11 is",optionA:"12",optionB:"11",optionC:"10",optionD:"13",correctOption:"optionB"},{question:"Highest common factor of 30 and 132",optionA:"6",optionB:"2",optionC:"34",optionD:"4",correctOption:"optionA"},{question:" A number that does not have a numeric of its own",optionA:"8",optionB:"1",optionC:"0",optionD:"2",
correctOption:"optionC"},{question:"Is Pie a rational or irrational number",optionA:"rational number",optionB:"irrational number",optionC:"both A and B",optionD:"it depends on question",correctOption:"optionB"},{question:"How many seconds are their in a day",optionA:"78009 sec",optionB:"98000 sec",optionC:"87400 sec",optionD:"86400 sec",correctOption:"optionD"},{question:"Who is the father of Mathematics",optionA:"Aryabhatta",optionB:"Archimedes",optionC:"Albert Einstein",optionD:"Samos John",correctOption:"optionB"},
{question:"What is the mathematical 'recipe' for working something out",optionA:"Shapes",optionB:"Equation",optionC:"Interest",optionD:"Formula",correctOption:"optionD"},{question:"Sum of all angles of a triangle is",optionA:"150",optionB:"360",optionC:"180",optionD:"300",correctOption:"optionC"},{question:"which of these number is not square?",optionA:"1936",optionB:"1024",optionC:"784",optionD:"931",correctOption:"optionD"},{question:"what is the anwer for 12x4=_____ ?",optionA:"12",optionB:"34",
optionC:"56",optionD:"48",correctOption:"optionD"},{question:"Arrange the 2,4,1,6,67,8,10 in ascending number ?",optionA:"1,2,4,6,8,10,67",optionB:"2,4,1,67,10,8,6",optionC:"6,8,10,2,4,1,67",optionD:"2,4,1,6,67,8,10",correctOption:"optionA"},{question:"what is the correct spelling for 42 ?",optionA:"forty-two",optionB:"fourty-two",optionC:"fourtytwo",optionD:"fortitwo",correctOption:"optionA"},{question:"what comes after 32 and before 34?",optionA:"32",optionB:"33",optionC:"34",optionD:"31",correctOption:"optionB"}];
let shuffledQuestions=[];function handleQuestions(){for(;9>=shuffledQuestions.length;){const a=questions[Math.floor(Math.random()*questions.length)];shuffledQuestions.includes(a)||shuffledQuestions.push(a)}}let questionNumber=1,playerScore=0,wrongAttempt=0,indexNumber=0;
function NextQuestion(a){handleQuestions();a=shuffledQuestions[a];document.getElementById("question-number").innerHTML=questionNumber;document.getElementById("player-score").innerHTML=playerScore;document.getElementById("display-question").innerHTML=a.question;document.getElementById("option-one-label").innerHTML=a.optionA;document.getElementById("option-two-label").innerHTML=a.optionB;document.getElementById("option-three-label").innerHTML=a.optionC;document.getElementById("option-four-label").innerHTML=
a.optionD}
function checkForAnswer(){const a=shuffledQuestions[indexNumber].correctOption,b=document.getElementsByName("option");let d=null;b.forEach(c=>{c.value===a&&(d=c.labels[0].id)});!1===b[0].checked&&!1===b[1].checked&&!1===b[2].checked&&0==b[3].checked&&(document.getElementById("option-modal").style.display="flex");b.forEach(c=>{!0===c.checked&&c.value===a?(document.getElementById(d).style.backgroundColor="green",playerScore++,indexNumber++,setTimeout(()=>{questionNumber++},1E3)):c.checked&&c.value!==
a&&(document.getElementById(c.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor="red",document.getElementById(d).style.backgroundColor="green",wrongAttempt++,indexNumber++,setTimeout(()=>{questionNumber++},1E3))})}function handleNextQuestion(){checkForAnswer();unCheckRadioButtons();setTimeout(()=>{9>=indexNumber?NextQuestion(indexNumber):handleEndGame();resetOptionBackground()},1E3)}
function resetOptionBackground(){document.getElementsByName("option").forEach(a=>{document.getElementById(a.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor=""})}function unCheckRadioButtons(){const a=document.getElementsByName("option");for(let b=0;b<a.length;b++)a[b].checked=!1}
function handleEndGame(){let a=null,b=null;3>=playerScore?(a="Bad Grades, Keep Practicing.",b="red"):4<=playerScore&&7>playerScore?(a="Average Grades, You can do better.",b="orange"):7<=playerScore&&(a="Excellent, Keep the good work going.",b="green");const d=playerScore/10*100;document.getElementById("remarks").innerHTML=a;document.getElementById("remarks").style.color=b;document.getElementById("grade-percentage").innerHTML=d;document.getElementById("wrong-answers").innerHTML=wrongAttempt;document.getElementById("right-answers").innerHTML=
playerScore;document.getElementById("score-modal").style.display="flex"}function closeScoreModal(){questionNumber=1;indexNumber=wrongAttempt=playerScore=0;shuffledQuestions=[];NextQuestion(indexNumber);document.getElementById("score-modal").style.display="none"}function closeOptionModal(){document.getElementById("option-modal").style.display="none"};